Guide to the Rainbow Triangle Oral History Collection UA.29.03.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Oral histories, 1
  - Palmquist, Ian, 41
    Director of Equality North Carolina, and active in several North Carolina LGBT organizations. Originally from Raleigh, North Carolina.
    - Ian Palmquist interview Tape 1, April 21, 2004 (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0063)
    - Ian Palmquist interview Tape 2, April 21, 2004 (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0064)
  - Perrier, Erica, 42
    Graduate of Duke, class of 2003. Active in field hockey while at Duke. Originally from Montreal.
    - Erica Perrier interview (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0065)
    - Erica Perrier transcript, paper by Monique Currie (interviewer), 2003 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Pham, Milan, 43
    Lawyer and former employee of Americans for a Fair Chance, and former director of the Orange County Human Rights and Relations Department.
    - Milan Pham interview, April 15, 2004 (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0066)
  - "Pollick, Michelle", 44
    Student Affairs employee at Duke University. Originally from Atlanta, Georgia.
    - Michelle Pollick interview, November 29, 2000 (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0067)
      Pseudonymous transcript to be used until February 20, 2073. Researchers must sign agreement to NOT use any identifying information contained in interview.
    - Michelle Pollick transcript, researcher agreement form, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Raines, Sara-Jane, 45
    Detective and firearms instructor with Duke Police; graduate of Duke (class of 1983), graduate of UNC-CH (MA, 1987); originally from Southern California.
    - Sara Jane Raines interview, November 17, 2000 (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0068)
    - Sara Jane Raines transcript, biographical information sheet, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Rosario, Jessica, 46
    - Jessica Rosario interview (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0069)
  - Rudy, Kathy, 47
    Professor of women's studies at Duke University, graduate of Duke (M.Div, 1989, and PhD, 1993); originally from Syracuse, New York.
    - Kathy Rudy interview, November 28, 2000 (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0070)
    - Kathy Rudy transcript, biographical information sheet, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Rutherford, Carlton, 48
    Licensed clinical social worker (LCSW), minister, and activist focusing on children and families, HIV/AIDS, LGBTQ community, people of color, and homelessness; graduate of Duke (M.Div 2005). Originally from Scotland Neck, North Carolina.
    - Carlton Rutherford interview Tape 1, October 3, 1999 (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0071)
    - Carlton Rutherford interview Tape 2, October 3, 1999 (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0072)
    - Carlton Rutherford interview Tape 3, October 3, 1999 (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0073)
  - Sherratt, Thomas, 49
    Psychologist and therapist, originally from Eastern North Carolina.
    - Thomas Sherrat interview, November 26, 2000 (Box 4, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0074)
    - Thomas Sharratt transcript, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Sherwood, Amie, 50
    - Amie Sherwood interview (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0075)
  - Smiley, Erica, 51
    Student at UNC-Chapel Hill at time of interview (graduated 2001), originally from Greensboro, North Carolina. As of 2016, Organizing Director for Jobs With Justice.
    - Erica Smiley interview Tape 1, March 23, 2001 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0076)
    - Erica Smiley interview Tape 2, April 5, 2001 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0077)
    - Erica Smiley biographical information sheet, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "Stone, Livvie", 52
    Staff member in Duke University Libraries. Originally from Tuscaloosa, Alabama.
    - Livvie Stone interview, November 14, 2000 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0078)
      No identifying information from interview is to be used in any publication, including on the internet; pseudonym must be used.
    - Livvie Stone transcript, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Taylor, Doris, 53
    Scientist and professor at Duke University Medical Center, Cardiology Division, at time of interview. As of 2016, Director of Regenerative Medicine Research at the Texas Heart Institute.
    - Doris Taylor interview (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0079)
    - Doris Taylor transcript, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Teasley, Alan, 54
    Teacher and administrator in Durham Public Schools; graduate of UNC-Chapel Hill (class of 1970, MAT 1971, PhD 1990); originally from Durham, North Carolina. As of 2016, adjunct professor in Duke's Master of Arts in Teaching program.
    - Alan Teasley interview (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0080)
    - Alan Teasley biographical information sheet, notes, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Tino, Michael, 55
    Director of Young Adult and Campus Ministry for the Unitarian Universalist Association; graduate of Duke (PhD 1998); originally from Brooklyn, New York.
    - Michael Tino interview Tape 1, April 24, 2003 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0081)
    - Michael Tino interview Tape 2, April 24, 2003 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0082)
    - Michael Tino transcript, resume, biographical information sheet, family history, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Tobin, Leslie, 56
    Mother of one and carpenter; graduate of Duke, class of 1976. Originally from Maryland.
    - Leslie Tobin interview Tape 1, November 29, 2000 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0083)
    - Leslie Tobin interview Tape 2, November 29, 2000 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0084)
    - Leslie Tobin transcript, paper by Kate Chomsky-Higgins (interviewer), 2000 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Unks, Gerald, 57
    Professor in School of Education at UNC-Chapel Hill, originally from Illinois.
    - Gerald Unks interview Tape 1, October 29, 2000 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0085)
    - Gerald Unks interview Tape 2, October 29, 2000 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0086)
    - Gerald Unks transcript, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Vicci, Leandra, 58
    Lecturer in Department of Computer Science at UNC-Chapel Hill.
    - Leandra Vicci interview Tape 1 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0087)
    - Leandra Vicci interview Tape 2 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0088)
  - Walker, Joan, 59
    Elementary school teacher and activist for LGBT issues; graduate of Duke, class of 1971. Originally from Kentucky.
    - Joan Walker Transcript, biographical information sheet, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Walton, April, 60
    As of 2016, the Learning Outreach Director at the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke.
    - April Walton interview (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0089)
  - Watson, Marki, 61
    - Marki Watson interview, April 19, 2004 (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0090)
    - unlabeled tape, possibly part of Marki Watson interview (Box 5, Audio-cassette UA29030001-CS-0091)
- Project materials, 2
  This series includes materials related to the planning, development, and implementation of the Rainbow Triangle Oral History project by staff and volunteers at the Duke Center for LGBT Life. Included is correspondence between Ian Lekus and others on planning the mission of the project, forms to be used, and how the collected interviews would be used, preserved, and made accessible to the wider community, among other topics.
  - List of interviewees (partial), undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Project background, research, and clippings, 1999-2001 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Project research materials, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Interview forms, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Project background and correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, clippings, and research materials, 1996-1999 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Notes on meeting with Special Collections staff, May 14, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and materials related to LGBT bar scene in Triangle, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - GLB Service Report and transcript, 2000, 2003
- Newspapers, 3
  This series includes newspapers featuring participants in the Rainbow Triangle Project or relating to LGBT life in the Triangle region. Several newspapers include stories based on interviews with Rainbow Triangle narrators conducted by Ian Lekus and Patrick Toal. Most issues of the Independent Weekly included in this series are Pink Triangle issues focusing on the LGBT community and related issues in the region.
  - The Front Page, October 22, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Vol. 20, No. 22
  - Independent Weekly, 1996-1998 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Pink Triangle issues. July 1996 is incomplete.
  - Independent Weekly, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Pink Triangle issues.
  - Independent Weekly, 2000, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Independent Weekly, 2003-2004 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Independent Weekly, 2005-2006 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Tobacco Road, December 1999/January 2000 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Vol. 22, Issue 1
  - Tobacco Road, April 2000 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Vol. 22, Issue 3